<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Some Random Weekend</title>
    <description>This is a collection of some random thoughts, #TILs, and some tips for myself. 
</description>
    <link>http://seimith.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://seimith.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 14:35:28 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 14:35:28 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Early Sunday Morning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Tom&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &quot;Hi, Tom&quot; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 08:22:15 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://seimith.github.io/jekyll/update/2016/06/11/Early-Sunday-Morning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seimith.github.io/jekyll/update/2016/06/11/Early-Sunday-Morning.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 1 General Assembly WDI SF</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just completed my first week of General Assembly’s Web Development Immersive program and I feel like I’ve been sitting with my classmates for months! Where to start?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About General Assembly WDI&lt;/strong&gt;
General Assembly’s Web Development Immersive (“WDI”) program is a 3-month coding program. One learns Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSON, and some more stuff that involves to many acronyms and numbers that I don’t remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-Work&lt;/strong&gt;
Before starting the program I had to complete some pre-work on Ruby, Git, HTML, and CSS. The HTML and CSS were great to refresh because I haven’t touched those things is years! Git was completely foreign to me, and Ruby was similar to JavaScript in terms of its functions/methods and classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week 1&lt;/strong&gt;
My first week was very interesting. After being out of college for a year and not doing anything remotely similar to coding/programming in years it was a very difficult transition for me to plummet into the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Terminal and GitHub: On the first day we went over some basic terminal and git commands. Learning how to navigate through the terminal was a bit scary for me. The laptop that I use isn’t mine so I was thoroughly irked out with using the terminal to create and delete things. GitHub was also very alien to me. I have never used GitHub for anything in my entire life! The concept of having to work locally, then adding/commiting/pushing my local files to a repository (“reopo”), and the  requesting for a pull for my instructors to merge my files in my repo to theirs’ was interesting to grasp at first. However, after using the terminal and GitHub for a good solid 3.75 days… I became completely comfortable with the terminal and I can sort of say that I GET GIT (I think)! On Friday (9/27) I was able to help my classmates with their Git problems! Am I a Git pro now? Just kidding.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important command that really helped me out was the following. It looks for and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; files and git removes it. It comes in handy when you’ve accidentally add/commit/and pushed the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; file to your repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;find . -name .DS_Store -print0 | xargs -0 git rm --ignore-unmatch&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the silliest problems that I have with Git is the over creation of .ds files in my repo. Using the above removes all .ds files so I can properly add, commit, and push my new files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ruby: As I mentioned previously, I’ve never seen or used Ruby… ever. The only exposure that I had with the language was with the pre-work. When we reviewed some basics on the first day I was like: Yeah, my life is nice and randy dandy. However, when we began to work on methods/functions and it’s scoping properties, I felt so silly. I realized that I don’t know how to think like a coder. When I approach a project, I think backwards. I’m not quite sure if that’s good, but I tend to get stuck on a solution because I tend to over think about how the outcome should be.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 08:22:15 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://seimith.github.io/jekyll/update/2013/09/30/Week-1-General-Assembly-WDI-SF.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seimith.github.io/jekyll/update/2013/09/30/Week-1-General-Assembly-WDI-SF.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
